So let's try a short exercise where we work with files and then we will practice
loops and our list comprehension and working with files.
If you have the course website open, you can download this file called cities.json and it
contains, let's take a look at it, just has the top five cities and their populations.
So we're going to import the JSON module which is built into the standard library and Python
and we're going to use that to help us parse the data.
I'm just going to exit my ripple here and get this file.
So now if I list here I should see the file in my directory called cities.json and I'm going
to open my ripple again. So if I want to work with JSON and the JSON library in Python,
I need to import it. It's not built in and then I want to use a context manager to open this
file so I'm going to use that with keyword and say with open cities.json and I'm going to use
another keyword called as to give this open file a name so that I can reference it later on.
So I'm going to say as city a file and then I can go ahead while I'm in this context manager
notice that I have tabbed into it. So all of the code that is intended under the statement
belongs to the context manager anything that is after it that is not intended is not going to
get run in the scope of the context manager. So I want to do my stuff with the file in the context
manager and then exit that block what I'm done. So I can say that the city's data is
JSON.load in the city's file and then I can print this out and I'm going to hit enter one more
time because now I'm done with this file. If I take a look at the type of city's data we'll see
that it's a list. If I take a look at the zero element we'll see that it's a dictionary. So what
this has returned is a list of dictionaries that mapped matches to the JSON file and then I can work
with it. I could use that pretty print function from earlier so from P print import P print to then
P print my list of city's data pretty print it in a more human readable format.